Marx, Hilde; Papers ger066
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Hilde Marx1936-1986
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Marx, Hilde
ger066
4.3
The collection contains the scrapbooks of Hilde Marx (1911-1986), a writer, poet, and journalist.
Collection X
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted. Scrapbooks 1, 2 and 4 are in very fragile condition. Access may be limited until conservation treatment may be implemented.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Note
Born in Germany, Hilde Marx (1911-1986) was a writer, poet, and journalist. She emigrated to the United States in 1938.
During the late 1960s and early 1970s, Marx wrote and stared in a one woman show offering monologues, commentary, and comedy sketches. Marx also traveled to take part in speaking engagements.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains 14 scrapbooks including correspondence, writings published in Aufbau (NY), programs from Hilde Marx's one woman shows, photographs, and ephemera. There are also match book covers of the places she stayed while traveling and, a Greyhound bus ticket showing when she traveled to Rohde Island. There are newspaper clippings of small publications that she wrote for and festival fliers.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged chronologically. There are no series.
Literature; Women authors; World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees; Correspondences; Scrapbooks
- Scrapbook One, 1936; 1938-1949; Undated (Oversized 1)
- Scrapbook Two, 1948-1950; 1952 (Oversized 2)
- Scrapbook Three, 1951-1952; 1955; 1962; Undated (Oversized 1)
- Scrapbook Four, 1950-1953; Undated (Oversized 4)
- Scrapbook Five, 1953-1956; Undated (Oversized 3)
- Scrapbook Six, 1956-1961 (Oversized 4)
- Scrapbook Seven, 1960-1966; Undated (Oversized 5)
- Scrapbook Eight, 1966-1969 (Oversized 5)
- Scrapbook Nine, 1966-1967; 1969-1971; Undated (Oversized 6)
- Scrapbook Ten, 1971-1973; Undated (Oversized 6)
- Scrapbook Eleven, 1973-1975 (Oversized 7)
- Scrapbook Twelve, 1975-1978 (Oversized 8)
- Scrapbook Thirteen, 1978-1982; Undated (Oversized 9)
- Scrapbook Fourteen, 1982-1986 (Oversized 10)